Finding Aid for Arvid Jouppi Papers, 1940-1987 (bulk 1963-1987)
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- William C. Roney & Co
  - Topical
    - Christiana Securities vs. U.S. 1971
      - Jouppi Statement, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Companies
      - Field Notes 1971 (Box 15)
      - Hancock Industries (Box 15)
      - National Mobile Concrete Organization 1971 (Box 15)
    - Forums, Roney Research Seminars 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 15)
      (Seminars on Auto Industry, includes memos, correspondence, and agendas)
    - Investors Diversified Services 1971 (Box 15)
    - Reports
      - Auto Industry 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Hagerman, Clyde: Auto Industry and Jouppi's activities 1971 (Box 15)
      - Special
        - "An Overview of the Outlook for Nuclear Power in the U.S....," 1971 (Box 15)
        - "Leverage," 1971 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence
    - 1967 (Box 15)
    - 1970 (Box 15)
    - 1971
      - General, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Resignation from Wm. C. Roney (Box 15)
- Delafield Childs, Inc.
  The Delafield Childs, Inc., series (2.5 linear feet) covers the years 1971-1975 when Jouppi worked for the New York firm as vice president and supervisory analyst. It is organized into three subseries: Administration, Topical, and Correspondence. The Administrative files are particularly valuable for the researcher interested in Jouppi's client relationships. The course of his contact with clients can be traced from the Client Contact Sheets, which are alphabetically arranged and document the years 1973-74. They provide information on the type of contact Jouppi made - telephone calls, mailings, or visits - and brief synopses of topics of discussion. The Institutional Client Contact Sheets describe, for each client during a given period of time, all of the contacts made by Delafield Childs analysts and the subjects under discussion.
  - Administrative
    - General: memos, financial statements, policy statements, etc.) (Box 16)
    - Capitalization of firm (Box 16)
      (see also Correspondence, Walter Delafield)
    - Clients
      - Commissions: correspondence and statements (Box 16)
      - Contact Sheets
        - A-C (Box 16)
          (D missing)
        - E-L (Box 16)
        - M-R (Box 16)
        - S-Z (Box 16)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
      - Lists (Box 16)
      - Subscriptions: requests and replies (Box 16)
    - Institutional Contact Sheets (Box 16)
    - Work Plans (Box 16)
  - Topical
    The results of the research which Jouppi conducted at Delafield, Childs can be found in the Topical subseries. There are a number of Company files, which were maintained by Jouppi on both client firms and those firms which he studied. The materials are of varying quality and range from correspondence, field visit notes, and conversation notes, to statistical operating records. In addition, Newsletters, under the titles "Cars," "Farm Machinery," and "Rubber," are arranged chronologically by year and month, and include analyses of past trends and projections of future economic directions. The researcher might encounter duplication of materials in the Company and Newsletter files.
    - Companies
      - Adams Express (Box 16)
      - Aetna (Box 16)
      - Alliance Capital Management Corporation (Box 16)
      - Arvin Industries (Box 16)
      - Bank of America (Box 16)
      - Bank of California (Box 16)
      - Banker's Trust Company (Box 16)
      - Boatmen's National Bank (Box 16)
      - Capital Research and Management Company (Box 16)
      - Caterpillar Tractor (Box 16)
      - Champion Spark Plug (Box 16)
      - Channing Management (Box 16)
      - Chase, John P (Box 16)
      - Chase Manhattan Bank (Box 16)
      - Chemical Bank New York Trust (Box 16)
      - Chrysler (Box 16)
      - Citizen's and Southern National Bank (Box 16)
      - Clark Equipment Company (Box 16)
      - College Retirement Equities Fund (Box 16)
      - Colonial Management Association (Box 16)
      - Connecticut General Life Insurance (Box 16)
      - Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance (Box 16)
      - Continental Illinois National Bank (Box 16)
      - Cooper Tire and Rubber Company (Box 16)
      - Crocker National Bank (Box 16)
      - Cummins Engine Company (Box 16)
      - Dana Corporation (Box 16)
      - Deere and Company (Box 16)
      - Deutsche Bank (West Germany) (Box 16)
      - Dreyfuss Fund (Box 16)
      - E. W. Axe and Company (Box 16)
      - Eaton Corporation (Box 16)
      - Echlin Corporation (Box 16)
      - Electric Storage Battery (Box 16)
      - Eltra Corporation (Box 16)
      - Equitable Life (Box 16)
      - Ex-Cello Corporation (Box 16)
      - Federal Mogul (Box 16)
      - Fidelity Management and Research Company (Box 16)
      - First National Bank of Chicago (Box 16)
      - First National City Bank (Box 16)
      - Flambeau Products Corporation (Box 16)
      - Ford Motor Company (Box 16)
      - Ford Motor of Canada (Box 16)
      - Ford Foundation (Box 16)
      - Fruehauf Corporation (Box 16)
      - General American Life Insurance (Box 16)
      - General Tire and Rubber Company (Box 16)
      - Genuine Parts Company (Box 16)
      - Girard Trust (Box 16)
      - Globe Union (Box 16)
      - Goodyear (Box 16)
      - Gould, Inc (Box 16)
      - Hamilton Management Corporation (Box 16)
      - John Hancock (Box 16)
      - Hancock Industries (Box 16)
      - Harris Trust and Savings (Box 16)
      - Harvester Truck Operations (Box 17)
      - Hayes-Albion Corporation (Box 17)
      - Houdaille Corporation (Box 17)
      - ISI Corporation (Box 17)
      - International Harvester (Box 17)
      - Investors Diversified Services (Box 17)
      - Keystone Custodian Funds (Box 17)
      - Libby-Owens Ford (Box 17)
      - Lincoln National Investment Advisory Corporation (Box 17)
      - Loomis Sayles and Company (Box 17)
      - Lutheran Brotherhood (Box 17)
      - McCord Corporation (Box 17)
      - McNeil Corporation (Box 17)
      - Madison Fund (Box 17)
      - Manufacturer's Hanover Trust (Box 17)
      - Metropolitan Life Insurance (Box 17)
      - Monroe Auto Equipment Company (Box 17)
      - Morgan Guaranty Trust (Box 17)
      - National Standard (Box 17)
      - New York Life Insurance (Box 17)
      - North American Rockwell (Box 17)
      - Northern Trust (Box 17)
      - Northland Aluminum Projects (Box 17)
      - Northwestern National Bank of Minneapolis; of St. Paul (Box 17)
      - Old Colony Trust Company (Box 17)
      - Prudential Insurance (Box 17)
      - Putnam Management Company (Box 17)
      - Reserve Funds Management (Box 17)
      - Rockwell International (Box 17)
      - St. Paul Companies (Box 17)
      - Scudder, Stevens and Clark (Box 17)
      - Securities Pacific National Bank (Box 17)
      - Standard Products (Box 17)
      - State of Minnesota, State Board of Investment (Box 17)
      - Sur-Vac (Box 17)
      - Transamerica Investment Research Inc (Box 17)
      - Tri-Continental Corporation (Box 17)
      - Trust Investment Counselor (Box 17)
      - Union Trust (Box 17)
      - United California Bank (Box 17)
      - U.S. Trust Company of New York (Box 17)
      - Vawter and Company (Box 17)
      - Wellington Management Company (Box 17)
      - Wells Fargo Bank (Box 17)
      - Western Asset Management (Box 17)
      - White Motor Company (Box 17)
      - Wilmington Trust (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Detroit VIP Day 1975 (Box 17)
    - Economic Projections (Box 17)
    - Farm Machinery Outlook (Box 17)
    - Financial Analysts Federation (Box 17)
    - Indonesia: field trip notes (Box 17)
    - "Library of Wall Street": publication of series of volumes on Wall Street activities (Box 17)
    - Newsletters
      - Cars
        - 1973 (Box 17)
          (includes undated)
        - 1974 (Box 17)
      - Farm Machinery 1972-1973 (Box 17)
      - Rubber 1972-1974 (Box 17)
    - New York Stock Exchange: compliance with exchange rules (Box 17)
    - Rubber Industry (Box 17)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission: brokers' commission rates (Box 17)
    - Seminars
      - General (Box 17)
      - Automobile Industry Related (Box 17)
      - Automotive Ecology (Box 17)
      - Ron Lewis: seminars for research analysts, Jouppi was an occasional moderator (Box 17)
      - Roundtables on Business and Economic Outlooks (Box 18)
      - Tire Companies (Box 18)
      - "A Wall Street Visit To Washington" (Box 18)
      - World Energy Conference (Box 18)
    - Steel Industry: brief notes (Box 18)
    - World Research Trip 1974 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence
    The Correspondence subseries is limited in quantity and is organized alphabetically and chronologically. Of specific interest is the correspondence between Jouppi and Walter Delafield, president of the firm, which sheds light on both their relationship to each other and on internal company policy matters.
    - Alphabetical
      - Delafield, Walter: mostly outgoing (Box 18)
      - Wright, James: investment in Delafield, Childs (Box 18)
    - Chronological 1971-1974 (Box 18)
- Arvid Jouppi Associates
  As Jouppi prepared to leave Delafield Childs he was already making plans to set up a research services firm, of which he would be president. Creating Arvid Jouppi Associates, or AJA as it is commonly known, was designed to emphasize Jouppi's belief that strong research is one of the most important components of sound business investing. The records of the Arvid Jouppi Associates series (5.5 linear feet) are divided into five subseries: Administrative, Topical, Michigan Research Center, "One of A Kind," and Correspondence. Throughout the AJA series, the researcher will find materials such as prayers, essays on the use of Christian principles in operating AJA, reflections on Jouppi's relationship with God, and other Christian narratives (in letter or report form), which document the influence of Jouppi's religious beliefs on all aspects of his life. These materials are important because they reflect what is on Jouppi's mind at various times regarding his business and personal lives. As a devout Christian, Jouppi was an evangelist among his associates, friends, and acquaintances. Although his correspondence with these people is, at times, intensely personal, it often includes informative histories of Jouppi's relationship to them.
  - Administrative
    The Administrative subseries contains records which relate to the development, administration, and maintenance of AJA, including the difficulties of running a one-man research firm. It can be used to study the ideas behind Jouppi's establishment of AJA; the business activities in which he participated on a daily basis, including field trips and public meetings of business leaders (see also Topical subseries, Forums files); and the difficulties he had in finding clients and competing with large investment research services companies.(see also Topical subseries, Reports, "Personal Story")
    - By-Laws 1978 (Box 18)
    - Clients
      - General, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Invoices 1980 (Box 18)
      - Mailings (Box 18)
      - Proposals (Box 18)
    - Colin Hochstin
      - Activity Reports and financial information 1977 (Box 18)
      - Researcher Assessments 1977 (Box 18)
        (Jouppi is discussed)
    - Financial Records
      - Housekeeping records (Box 18)
      - Income tax and year end expenditures 1980-1983, 1985 (Box 18)
    - Form Letters (Box 18)
    - Future Development
      - Reflections and ideas 1976 (Box 18)
      - Solicitation of advice 1982, 1985 (Box 18)
    - John Muir 1979-1982 (Box 18)
      (includes material on liquidation of John Muir and financial records)
    - Lease 1976-1977 (Box 18)
    - Personnel Announcements 1975 (Box 18)
    - Prayers for the Day (Box 18)
    - Trenn, William: senior associate for AJA 1982 (Box 18)
    - Work Plans 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Topical
    Those materials which relate to Jouppi's research regarding the automobile and related industries can be found in the Topical subseries, Reports, Studies, and Company files. This documentation is thorough; all reports generated by the firm for the years 1974-1985 are found here. The Reports files include both narratives and statistical compilations. From them the researcher can study both Jouppi's methodological approach as well as his findings on industry patterns. The Studies files consists of materials from specific company studies or studies of specific aspects of the automobile industry. As with other series in this collection, the researcher will find individual Company files which also can be used to study Jouppi's research methods and the findings from his efforts.
    There are other materials of interest in the Topical subseries. They include records and transcripts from several Congressional hearings in which Jouppi testified; materials concerning actual and proposed business ventures, including one related to investment research; and Jouppi reflections and studies on the automobile industry in Japan.
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Labor, Industry, Education, Government: proposal 1981 (Box 18)
    - American Institute of Chemical Engineers 1981 (Box 18)
    - Bartholemew, Stanley: oil company 1975 (Box 18)
    - Clippings
      - General 1978 (Box 18)
      - Scrapbooks, unbound
        - Scrapbook 1, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - Scrapbook 2-3 (Box 19)
    - Companies
      - American Motors Company 1982, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Borg-Warner 1982-1985 (Box 19)
      - Caterpillar Tractor 1975 (Box 19)
      - Chrysler Corporation
        - General 1975, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
        - Research Contract 1985-1986 (Box 19)
      - Dana Corporation 1978 (Box 19)
      - Dayco Corporation 1978, 1979, 1982, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Detroit Forge 1982 (Box 19)
      - Federal Mogul 1982, 1985, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Flambeau Plastics (Box 19)
      - Ford Motor Company 1981-1984 (Box 19)
      - General Motors 1975, 1980 (Box 19)
      - Gould Incorporated 1977 (Box 19)
      - Grace Company 1981 (Box 19)
      - Grewell Diecast Products 1978 (Box 19)
      - Gulf and Western Industries 1983 (Box 19)
      - Harbridge House, Incorporated 1978 (Box 19)
      - Mack Trucks 1982 (Box 19)
      - Massey Ferguson 1985 (Box 19)
      - Mazda 1983 (Box 19)
      - Midland Ross 1975-1976, 1980 (Box 19)
      - Midwest Forge 1981-1985 (Box 19)
      - Morgan Stanley and Company 1977 (Box 19)
      - Multifastener Corporation 1984-1985 (Box 19)
      - Numex 1980-1981 (Box 19)
      - Rockwell International 1980, 1984 (Box 19)
      - Sigma Management Services 1975 (Box 19)
      - Signal Companies 1978 (Box 19)
      - Stifel, Nicolaus and Company 1974 (Box 19)
      - Subaru 1985 (Box 19)
      - Sun Electric 1983 (Box 19)
      - Sure-Vac 1975, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Taylor Forge 1985 (Box 19)
      - Toyota Hagen 1985 (Box 19)
      - United States Trust 1983 (Box 19)
      - White Motor Company 1981 (Box 19)
    - Congressional Testimony
      - Auto and Truck Manufacturing: furnished to Interstate Commerce Commission 1975 (Box 19)
      - Clean Air Act 1981 (Box 19)
      - Diesel Fuel 1982 (Box 19)
      - Emission Control 1982 (Box 19)
      - Federal Role in Developing Automotive Technology 1981 (Box 19)
      - Oversight Hearing on Chrysler: Chrysler financial difficulties and government bailout 1979 (Box 19)
    - Crandall's Business Index: research briefs (Box 20)
    - Detroit Investor's Research Wire (Box 20)
    - Economic Club of Detroit: Advisory Committee 1984 (Box 20)
    - Enercol Company: oxidation of waste 1982 (Box 20)
    - Exams, Stocks and Financing 1967 (Box 20)
    - Forums
      - American Automotive Leasing Association: Jouppi's remarks 1980 (Box 20)
      - Auto Markets outside the U.S.: Notes 1980 (Box 20)
      - "Automotive News; World Congress," 1982 (Box 20)
        (includes Jouppi's reactions to presentations)
      - Boston Boulevard Party 1979 (Box 20)
      - Detroit Renaissance Forums
        - General 1981-1984 (Box 20)
        - Company-Related 1980-1985, 2 folders (Box 20)
          (includes agendas, rosters, financial, correspondence, programs)
        - Specialty Forums, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - "Financial Capabilities-Global North American Scenes," 1984 (Box 20)
      - John Muir-"Mobile Conferences" on Automobile Industry 1978 (Box 20)
      - Keane Securities-International Trade Issues 1986 (Box 20)
      - National Association of Investment Clubs: Jouppi's remarks 1979 (Box 20)
      - Ron Lewis Seminars (Box 20)
        (contains some earlier materials)
      - "Wall Street Transcript": roundtable discussions on automobile industries (Box 20)
      - "Wall Street Visit to Detroit" (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Great Lakes Money Fund 1982 (Box 20)
    - International Partnership Group: publishing a book 1983-1985 (Box 20)
    - Investment Capital Ventures
      - Buried treasure 1985 (Box 20)
      - Petroleum 1986 (Box 20)
    - Investment Mission to Japan 1980-1985, 2 folders (Box 20)
      (mostly correspondence)
    - Investor's Service Bureau 1985 (Box 20)
    - JAMA Forum: Jouppi manuscript on Japanese manufacturing 1985 (Box 20)
    - Land Buying Project 1984 (Box 20)
    - Management Forecasting: proposals for 1977 (Box 20)
    - Michigan Investment Research
      - General 1979-1981 (Box 20)
        (includes development plans)
      - Field Reports, Interviews, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Notes: handwritten, miscellaneous, and undated (Box 20)
    - Oil Drilling Project 1981-1982 (Box 21)
    - "Perspectives": newsletter issues 1983-1984 (Box 21)
    - Rating Forms for Automobiles (Box 21)
    - Recess Club 1983 (Box 21)
    - Reiswerber, Marie T.: Jouppi testimony in estate litigation 1977 (Box 21)
    - Reports, Automobile and Related Industries
      - General, 4 folders (Box 21)
        (includes narrative thoughts, reflections, outlooks, and report drafts)
      - Keane Securities: reports generated by Jouppi for Keane Securities (Box 21)
      - Rooney Pace: worksheets generated by Jouppi 1981 (Box 21)
      - Special
        - "Biographical Data; 1975 Business Concepts" (Box 21)
        - "Detroit Renaissance Fights Decay": published in the M/G Financial Weekly 1975 (Box 21)
        - "An Economic Overview of the Durable Goods and Automotive Sectors in the U.S. in the 1980s" (Box 21)
        - "The Global Outlook for the Automotive Industry," 1982 (Box 21)
        - "Japanese Business Travel: July 1980," 1985 (Box 21)
        - "Personal Story": narrative by Jouppi on the development of AJA 1975 (Box 21)
        - "Preservation of our Industrial Complex and the Free Enterprise System," 1985 (Box 21)
        - "A Quiet New Breeze Flows Freshly Through Windows Broken in the Glass House, Parts 1 and 2," 1978 (Box 21)
        - "A Sharing of a Totally Different Pathway Toward Choosing the Reagan-Bush Ticket for November 4," 1980 (Box 21)
      - Statistical
        - General: statistical tables and worksheets on sales, earnings, parts, imports, exports, etc., 2 folders (Box 21)
        - Companies: operating records, includes data on sales, sales earnings, assets, and liabilities (Box 21)
        - Projections and Outlooks (Box 21)
    - Round the World Trip: notes and correspondence 1974 (Box 21)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission (Box 21)
    - Swiss Banks: around the world research journey 1983 (Box 21)
    - Studies
      - AT&T "Long Lines" Study: study on aspects of communications industry for AT&T, includes correspondence, interviews, and reports 1980-1981 (Box 21)
      - Cummins Diesel Engine Study: interviews 1981 (Box 21)
      - Dana Corporation Study: interviews with representatives and dealers 1981 (Box 21)
      - Dental Study: correspondence re: dental and veterinary industries 1983 (Box 21)
      - Federal Mogul Study 1981 (Box 21)
      - Goodyear Study: study of the tire industry, chiefly interviews 1981 (Box 21)
      - International Harvester Scout Study: interviews 1981 (Box 21)
      - Japanese Auto Parts Study 1982 (Box 21)
      - John Deere Study: interviews 1981 (Box 21)
      - Leather Steering Wheel Cover Study: interviews 1981 (Box 21)
      - Rebate Response Study, John DeLorean Study: interviews with industry representatives 1981 (Box 21)
      - Transmission Project 1984 (Box 21)
        (includes correspondence and raw data)
      - White Motor Company, Shell Oil/Chicago, Ex-Cell-O Corporation: interviews 1981 (Box 21)
    - World Research Center: planning memo (Box 21)
  - Michigan Research Center
    The Michigan Research Center was run by Jouppi in conjunction with several Wall Street firms with which he was affiliated. The Michigan Research Center subseries is arranged topically, and is primarily comprised of Reports generated by Jouppi on the automobile industries. The reports take the form of outlooks, projections, statistical data on growth, earnings, sales and expenditures, as well as announcements and agendas for conferences, Jouppi's reflections on business, and information pertinent to major companies. The researcher may find duplication of materials generated by the Michigan Research Center in the Topical and "One of a Kind" subseries.
    - Auto Economics Brief 1980 (Box 22)
    - Companies
      - Dayco Corporation (Box 22)
      - Toyota 1984 (Box 22)
    - Dirks, Ray: correspondence (Box 22)
    - Japanese Business Travel 1980 (Box 22)
    - Reflections and Ideas 1977-1981 (Box 22)
    - Reports
      - 1977 Colin, Hochstin, includes drafts, 4 folders (Box 22)
      - 1978 John Muir, 4 folders (Box 22)
      - 1979 John Muir (Box 22)
      - 1980-1981 John Muir (Box 22)
  - "One of A Kind" Notebooks
    The "One of a Kind" subseries (1978-1986), designated as such by Jouppi, is a collection of business materials which he maintained separately in chronological order by year and month. These documents, which include correspondence, reports, and conference notes and agendas, are a valuable representation of Jouppi's business interests for the year. The researcher will find overlap between this subseries and the Chronological series.
    - 1974-1975 June-February (Box 22)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 22)
    - 1980 (Box 22)
    - 1981 (Box 22)
    - 1982 (Box 23)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 23)
    - 1985
      - May-October (Box 23)
      - "Book Two" (Box 23)
    - 1986
      - May-December, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Correspondence
    The Correspondence subseries is limited in quantity but does pertain to important AJA business affairs. It should be used to supplement the other subseries.
    - Topical
      - Board of Directors: service on outside company boards (Box 23)
      - Ross, Percy, Syndicated Column: letters from readers asking Jouppi for financial advice 1985 (Box 23)
    - Chronological
      - 1975 (Box 23)
      - 1976 (Box 23)
      - 1977-1979 (Box 23)
      - 1980 (Box 23)
      - 1981 (Box 23)
      - 1982 (Box 23)
      - 1983 (Box 23)
      - 1984 (Box 23)
      - 1985 (Box 23)
- Writings
  In the Writings series (.5 linear feet), the final series in the collection, the most important item is a 373 page manuscript by Jouppi entitled "Automotive Heads and Tales." In Jouppi's own words, it is intended to be "a combination of automobilia, stories of related Wall Street research activity and reports on associated involvements by the governments of the United States, Canada, and Japan and several other nations." It is a broad, historical look at the automotive industry, and offers insight into Jouppi's relationships with leaders in the industry.
  - "Automotive Heads and Tales": Jouppi manuscript (Box 24)
  - "A du Pontless General Motors Had Lost A Little Of Its Value": no author (Box 24)
  - "Panorama Of Selected Operation Information On The U.S. Automotive Industry": no author (Box 24)
  - "Survival Of Small Business Is In Your Hands": no author (Box 24)